[ radio static hissing ]
- Mrs. French 's cat is missing .
The signs are posted all over town .
" Have you seen Honey ? "
We 've all seen the posters ,
but nobody has seen Honey the cat ,
nobody , until last Thursday morning ,
when Miss Collette Piscine swerved her car
to miss Honey the cat as she drove across a bridge .
Well , this bridge , now slightly damaged ,
is a bit of a local treasure
and even has its own fancy name ,
Pont de Flaque .
Now , Colette -
that sounds like " culotte . "
That 's " panty " in French .
And " Piscine " means " pool . "
Panty pool .
" Flaque " also means " pool " in French ,
so Colette Piscine , in French , Panty Pool ,
drives over the Pont de Flaque ,
the Pont de Pool , if you will ,
to avoid hitting Mrs. French 's cat
that has been missing in Pontypool .
Pont de Pool . Pontypool .
Panty pool .
Pont de Flaque .
What does it mean ?
Well , Norman Mailer , he had an interesting theory
that he used to explain the strange coincidences
in the aftermath of the JFK assassination .
In the wake of huge events , after them and before them ,
physical details , they spasm for a moment .
They sort of unlock .
And when they come back into focus ,
they suddenly coincide in a weird way .
Street names and birthdates and middle names ,
all kind of superfluous things appear related to each other .
It 's a ripple effect .
So what does it mean ?
Well , it means something 's going to happen ,
something big .
But then , something 's always about to happen .
Ronald Klein went peaceful in his 73rd year
at the Campbellford Hospital .
He left his loving wife of 51 years and three children -
No , no , I think it 's got to be you .
You got to be the worst fucking agent in the world .
Come on .
It 's not enough to say I 'm working .
It 's not enough .
Do you understand ?
Well , if you think it 's enough ,
then maybe we 're not thinking the same way .
You know what I mean ?
Peter Hopper went peacefully in his own home .
He leaves Edna , his loving wife of 51 years -
You know-you know what - you know what , Rick ?
You know what ?
You 're fired .
After a long struggle with illness .
Good .
Now we 're both in the same boat .
In her 84th year .
She is survived by 11 children
and 57 grandchildren .
Oh , Jesus .
[ cell phone ringing ]
Brought to you by Kawartha Lake Monuments .
Memories are forever ,
and so are Kawartha Lake 's Grand Monuments .
Cast your memories in stone with Kawartha Lake Monuments .
[ woman shouting indistinctly ]
- What ?
Hey !
- Hey !
- Who are you ?
- Who are you ? Who are you ?
Who are you ?
- CLSY Beacon Radio ,
your beacon on the region .
You 're listening to " Mazzy in the Morning , "
with your host Grant Mazzy .
- Morning , folks .
Mazzy here as he should be .
And here 's hoping the road will rise to meet us all today .
I got a couple things to take care of first here ,
a little housekeeping .
The staff and all the kids at the Tiny People 's Little People Daycare
want to get a couple of birthdays on the air .
Charlie Yupgo is turning six today ,
and ...
Griffin and Camille Jones turn 6 and 4 .
I guess that 's a brother and a sister
with the same birthday or not .
Hey , we want to say happy birthday ,
Charlie , Griffin , and Camille , however you may be related .
There , now -
Okay , Mazzy , come on , boy , please .
Be positive .
- Morning , Mr. Mazzy .
- Good morning , Laurel-Ann .
- Loved your " Isn 't it Ironic " this morning .
Love Norman Mailer .
- Thanks .
You know , it takes a girl with big feet
to dig old Norm .
So did you get me the good stuff ?
Ooh .
Mm .
Hey .
- Let 's make radio .
- And , Laurel-Ann , do me a favor .
Look up all the information you can on 911 calls ,
how many in a 24-hour period , how many hang-ups ,
that sort of thing , okay ?
And thanks .
Let 's make radio .
- You can play your June game today .
So swing those February blahs away
and go green today at Green Balls Driving Range .
- ♪ C-I-S-Y . ♪
♪ My beacon radio . ♪
♪ C-I-S-Y . ♪
- Mm .
- CLSY , Beacon Radio ,
your beacon on the region .
You 're listening to " Mazzy in the Morning "
with your host Grant Mazzy .
- Good morning , Pontypool .
This is Radio 660 , The Beacon ,
down here in the dungeon
under the street they call Drum .
I 'll be banging the drum for you all morning .
I 'm Grant Mazzy ,
and as always , I 'll be taking no prisoners .
Now -
Mm .
I got my coffee here .
And take a look outside .
I 'd say that 's our top story for today , folks .
Now , I had a strange experience
on my way into work this morning ,
and I 'd like to get some advice from you people later on .
When do you call 911 ?
Think about it .
I should mention , our producer ,
the lovely and talented Miss Sydney Briar is here .
And lucky Laurel-Ann Drummond ,
she 'll be our technical cowgirl today .
Now , I didn 't know this .
Maybe you did .
But this is news to me .
Laurel-Ann did a tour of duty in Afghanistan not too , too long ago .
- Well , you 're right there , new guy .
Everybody does know .
She was the grand master of last year 's fall fair .
Yesterday 's news .
- Hey .
- Oh , sorry , Laurel-Ann .
- I wasn 't the grand master .
I was the homecoming hero .
- Okay , I am sorry .
Okay , I am very bad .
- Ooh , Sydney , Sydney , Sydney .
Come on , girl .
- I 'm sorry . - It 's okay .
- Oh , you just heard an on-air apology from Sydney Briar .
She probably owes Laurel-Ann quite a few more .
Stay tuned .
Now , in our top story today ,
a big , cold , dull , dark , white , empty ,
never-ending , blow-my-brains-out ,
seasonal-affective-disorder , freaking-kill-me-now ,
weather front that 'll last all day .
Well , maybe when the wind shifts later on ,
we 'll get a little greenhouse gas relief
from the industrial South .
Hail Mary , yea , though I walk ,
we go to Ken Loney in the Sunshine Chopper .
- It 's always brighter above the clouds , Grant .
- Hey , Ken , how you doing ?
How are things in that bird up there ?
You gonna stay in that bird up there during the storm ?
- Yes , sir .
Yes , siree .
- Well , that can 't be safe .
Is that safe , Ken ?
- Well , I 'll be up here , Grant , on storm watch ,
watching all the routes in and around our region .
- Really ?
- Really , yep .
- Okay , Ken .
Boy , I wouldn 't want to be a bird if this storm hits
the way it 's supposed to .
- Don 't call me girl , by the way , Grant .
And leave Ken alone .
- Go slow , folks . We do have a tractor -
- I think he 's just concerned .
- Carrying wind generator blades along the 401 .
So slow going eastbound .
That 's it from the Sunshine Chopper .
Remember , drink Zap Fruit .
Gets you up . Keeps you going .
- Thank you , Ken Loney .
Breaking news out of Caesarea this morning .
Come on , boy . There we go .
Breaking news .
The Ontario Provincial Police are reporting a major bust
of a significant grow operation
in a quiet cul-de-sac in that town .
Constable Howard Ing says it 's a sign of things to come .
- These operations in suburban small-town neighborhoods
are the grow method of choice -
- You smoke pot , Syd ?
- Yes , I do .
Don 't make global warming jokes .
- Why , I didn 't make a joke .
I quoted the Bible .
There 's no jokes in the Bible .
- Speaking of the Bible , we are in a church ,
not a dungeon .
- Thanking you , Constable Howard Ing
of the Ontario Provincial Police .
You know , our local pot growers
are engaged in a deadly serious business ,
deadly booby traps ,
protecting their operations from prying eyes .
Land mines have been found -
- Cool it , Grant .
- They have vicious attack dogs and enough ammunition
to arm a small country .
Now , these are family neighborhoods , folks .
If Junior throws a ball through one of their windows ,
he 's just liable to trigger a death squad .
- What are you doing ?
- My producer Sydney 's talking in my ear .
Luckily , you can 't hear her .
- Okay , nobody cares , Grant -
- Sydney says nobody cares . Maybe she 's right .
- You forgot to do the closures after the billboard .
- I think you do care , region .
Taking no prisoners .
You know what that means ?
It means full disclosure , whatever the consequence .
- Not full disclosure , Grant , school closures .
I need you to read the school closures .
That 's what people need .
- This is Radio 660 ,
the Beacon .
Hey , you can 't just cut me off like that !
Jesus .
- Okay , you know , Grant , the whole full disclosure shtick
works better in a bigger context .
- Well , actually , it 's what got me fired .
- Well , there 's that too .
The thing is is that small towns ,
they already come without prisoners .
It 's called gossip ,
and it 's way ahead of you .
- No , no , Sydney , I 'm not talking about gossip .
I 'm talking about building a relationship
with my listeners ,
you know , shaking ' em up a little bit .
- Okay , we do news , weather , sports , local spots .
That 's what I need you to do .
What the hell do you think you have to disclose to us anyways ?
I mean , what is this that you think we need to hear from you ?
- I don 't know .
Well , actually , I do know , Sydney .
I am trying to piss a few people off
because that 's how it 's done .
Simple as that .
You see , a pissed-off listener is a wide-awake listener .
And he ain 't gonna change the station .
In fact , he may just call his pissed-off brother
and get him to listen too .
And then his pissed-off brother ,
he might call his pissed-off - I don 't know-preacher .
And that , Lady Briar ,
is how you build a loyal listening audience .
- Okay , well , I -
That all sounds perfectly pleasant , I 'm sure , okay ?
You know , Grant , you 're first-rate .
You 're doing a first-rate job .
But just let me tell you something .
Small towns , they 're fiercely proud places
with proud people , people who need to know
if the school bus is coming .
And so if you come in here with your " take no prisoners " this
and your " pissing everyone off " that ,
people are just gonna think you 're a dick .
- Okay . Okay .
- I mean , you 're going to embarrass and alienate -
- Yeah , okay . I said " okay . "
- Sorry .
Just the reality .
Okay , Grant , I want your Mazzy-ness .
I hired your Mazzy-ness .
I want the Mazzy-ness .
I just need the Mazzy-ness to come in a little slower ,
a little more get to know you ,
a little - little slower .
- Yeah , I get it .
I 'm not stupid .
- That 's not what I meant .
- I wanted to hear what he was gonna say .
- Come on .
He was just gonna talk about himself .
- Okay , Pontypool , good morning .
You know , I want to talk to you about something
that has been bugging me all morning .
[ suspenseful music ]
- Who are you ? Who are you ?
Who are you ?
- Here 's my question , Pontypool .
Here 's my story .
Now , look , I 'm driving into work today ,
and I pull up to the stop sign at Drum and Main .
And it 's 6 : 30 in the morning , and it 's cold ,
and it 's dark .
And suddenly , this woman appears out of nowhere .
I didn 't hit her or anything .
My car wasn 't even moving .
All of a sudden , she 's at my passenger window .
She 's babbling something ,
but I can 't understand her .
I can 't hear her . I don 't know what it is .
And then , poof .
She 's gone .
Cold morning .
So what do I do ?
Do I call 911 ?
Who do I call ?
No one ?
Our number is 519-555-3486 .
Let me know what I got to do .
- CLSY , Beacon Radio ,
your beacon on the region .
This Sunday , St. Luke 's Anglican Church
presents " Esther 's Story , "
a puppet show for all ages .
It tells the story of young Esther 's bravery
and willingness to trust God and -
- Good morning .
Oh , where are you calling from ?
Uh-huh .
And what would you like to say to Grant this morning ?
I 'm sorry . What ?
- Has Mrs. Tripp called in yet ?
- No .
That 's weird .
- Mrs. Tripp never , ever , ever misses a day .
And where 's Roger ?
It 's almost 10 : 00 .
- What are those ?
- Grant gave us Valentines .
You can put ' em up somewhere .
You know , he - he 's doing okay .
So okay , sweetheart , I 'm gonna call Mrs. Tripp .
Something 's coming in on the radio .
Roger , where are you ?
- Yeah , roger that .
We still have a code 48 in progress at the Fish Hut .
- Sydney ! Syd !
- Has requested backup .
Weapons present . 10-4 .
Roger that .
Sandy Hook and Wilmont , code 48 .
- Okay , so what 's code 48 , Laurel-Ann ?
- It means we have a hostage situation .
- There 's some confusion .
- There 's nothing on the wire
so I 'm gonna key it in right off the police radio .
- Really ? There 's nothing on the wire ?
Okay , so let 's not do anything with this yet .
- 32 % are pranks .
- Yeah , no , I 'm not getting anything either .
Whatever you do , don 't feed this into Grant yet .
- You may need to save your life .
- Ah , shit .
- With your host , Grant Mazzy .
- Yeah , Grant , it 's Gordon calling .
I just want to throw this idea out there
about the 911 .
What if you had another number that was-I don 't know -
say , like , 912 or something
that was not for total emergencies .
So if you had a bit of a gray area
and you weren 't sure whether you wanted to call 911 ,
you 'd call 912 .
I just have a feeling it might catch on .
I think it 's something people might , you know , take to .
- Gord , that 's a great idea .
You should be running the world .
Pontypool , my Pontypool ,
we interrupt our call-in segment
to bring you breaking news out of our area this morning .
Out on Sandy Hook and Wilmont , we have a hostage situation .
Two men are holding a van load of people at gunpoint .
The van is apparently towing a fishing hut .
Sporadic gunfire -
- Okay , lose the story , Grant .
We 're going to Ken Loney .
We 're going to the Sunshine Chopper .
- No one knows as yet what these hostage takers want
or whether or not they even know .
- They 're all drunk , Grant .
It 's the end of ice fishing season .
- But this being the end of ice fishing season ,
ice hut removal time ,
the chances that everyone on the ice this morning
is drunk is a very distinct reality .
Drunk ice fishermen and dare I say , drunk policemen ,
drunk officers of the law ,
drunk Ontario Provincial Police .
This is not yet confirmed by our sources , of course ,
but police , possibly drunk ,
are reporting that the hostage situation
has resolved itself .
They have two suspects in custody ,
both unarmed , as it turns out .
And the three people they were holding up
in fact fled the scene .
One can only hope that breaking news theme music
will accompany this story at some point .
There we go .
Oh , the state of drunkenness have leveled off
to acceptable levels this morning
as Buddy Bob Roseland and Dead-Eye Derek McCormack ,
O.P.P. Pontypool Division -
- Wrap it up , Grant .
- The hostage situation .
We 'll be back with updates as the situation hiccups .
We now go to Ken Loney in the Sunshine Chopper
for a little perspective on your morning drive .
Keep an eye out for crazy ladies in the snow ,
and remember , wherever you 're headed ,
get there safe .
- Hey , good morning .
It 's your buddy Ken high up in the Sunshine Chopper .
Routes look fine , building normally .
- Oh , come on .
You people got to learn to laugh at yourselves sometimes .
- The story 's not funny .
Derek McCormack is an alcoholic .
Bob Roseland is an alcoholic .
They 're trying to keep their jobs .
- Oh .
- Derek 's my brother-in-law ,
ex-brother-in-law .
- Ouch .
- Grant ?
- Hm ?
- Ken Loney 's not in a chopper .
- What ?
- The Sunshine Chopper is Ken 's Dodge Dart .
He plays sound effects .
Ken sits up on a hill for his aerial view .
And people are thrilled to have him up there in the sky
flying around in his Sunshine Chopper ,
even though .
- Oh , man , I bet they are .
Okay .
Syd ?
- Yeah .
- I hate winter .
- Everybody does .
- No , not like me .
These late winters ,
I feel like I 'm living in the basement of the world .
It 's so cold and so dark .
- Yeah .
- Yes , sir .
- Well , you 're gonna be okay .
Oh , and , Grant ,
I 'll tell you what .
When the whole fish hut story gets confirmed ,
we 'll bring it straight to you right away , okay ?
And it 's yours , even if it 's not legitimate .
You can do your whole " take no prisoner " thing , okay ?
- And you 'll find it funny this time ?
- I 'll find it as funny as I did the last time .
I bet you .
I was talking to Constable Roseland .
He 's totally serious .
He has completely freaked .
Something happened this morning on the ice ,
and it 's put them all into a state .
And now he wants us to drop the story .
- Drop it ?
- Well , it 's probably nothing , right ?
Probably just a hoax .
Anyways , we got the " Lawrence of Arabia " cast coming in ,
so we 're gonna brighten up the day with that .
- Laurel-Ann here .
Okay , okay .
It 's Ken Loney .
- Hey , Ken .
Oh , Ken , slow down .
Yeah .
Ken , where are you ?
Okay .
Ken , slow down .
Slow down .
And how many ?
Okay .
Okay , Ken , just a second .
Okay , wrap up Pontypool Corner , Grant .
We have a big story breaking .
Listen to me . Keep it hard .
- Says here -
- Okay , Ken , just a second .
- They 'll have a cab sitting in the lot all night .
- Just a second . We 're going live .
- Buck and doe double bill this weekend .
So I 'll check it out and make sure it 's right
that they 're both at the same time ,
but that 's what it looks like .
We have breaking news out of our region this morning .
It appears -
it seems that a large group of people have gathered
outside the offices of Dr. John Mendez .
It appears to be a protest of some kind ,
and officials are describing the crowd as " unruly . "
Now , Dr. John Mendez , you may recall ,
he was under investigation
for writing unnecessary prescriptions .
We have an exclusive live report from Ken Loney
in the - in the Sunshine Chopper .
What can you see there , Ken ?
- Grant , I am - I 'm watching hundreds ,
literally hundreds of people packed in
and around this building ,
and it looks pretty awesome up here .
They seem to be trying to cram themselves inside -
oh , whoa .
- What 's happening , Ken ?
- The side of the office ,
this building has just burst outward .
It 's spilling people .
It 's just kind of exploded .
Oh ! Oh , Jesus !
It 's an explosion of - of people .
Oh , my God !
Uh , people are getting trampled .
These people are getting killed down there .
Oh ! Ah !
- Ken , do you see any police ?
Is anybody trying to restore order ,
um , down there ?
- No ! No , I don 't see -
Wait , wait , wait , wait .
There 's a convoy of trucks and military vehicles .
Where did they come from ?
What the hell ?
There 's helicopters .
Uh -
there 's a helicopter at , like , 2 o 'clock and 1 -
Holy shit .
I got to back up out of here .
- Okay , Ken .
Ken , get safe .
Just try to get out of there .
- The road is blocked .
There 's definitely fatalities here , down there .
People just died , Grant .
I don 't know what the hell has just happened .
- Well , we 're gonna have to see if we can -
- Grant ? - Ken , we 're -
Ken ?
Are you there , Ken ?
- Okay , we 've got nothing on this , Grant .
- We 've got to get some information
on what is currently happening .
- Christ , this is five kilometers from here .
- Not more than three - five kilometers
from the station itself .
- Don 't say a lot , Grant .
We need to get this confirmed somehow .
- Something has happened at a doctor 's office
here in Pontypool involving a possible riot .
- I can 't get through to the O.P.P.
- Clearly , something has happened
here in Pontypool .
- Okay , we 've lost Ken . Go to break .
Go to recap , Grant .
- Describe what he saw or at least ...
what he thinks he saw .
You know , the French philosopher Roland Barthes
once described trauma as a news photo without a caption ,
and that , folks , is what I think we have here now .
- ♪ C-I-S-Y , Pontypool . ♪
♪ C-I-S-Y . ♪
- Did you get Ken back ?
We 're trying .
We 're trying on getting Ken back .
We 're trying to reach the police .
Grant , we still have nothing on the wire on this entire story .
Laurel-Ann and I are gonna work the phones .
We 're gonna work our sources .
We gonna try to find out something solid we can put on the air .
- Okay , and what do you want me to do ?
- Okay , well , Lawrence and the Arabians have -
have come all this way .
Nancy , how are you ?
- You 've got to be fucking kidding me .
- Come on , Grant .
I don 't need you to be a problem right now .
- But Sydney , Sydney .
We got the hook in .
You can 't just cut the line like that .
- Look , I just need you to do your job .
These fine people , you 're gonna interview them ,
and then they 're gonna sing a song .
- Sydney , do you really think
that this is what our audience is expecting
to hear from us right now ?
- So Laurel-Ann and I will dig up a story on this
that we can put on the air .
Thank you .
- Okay .
Okay , fine .
Let 's do it .
Let 's find out how the fuck rehearsals are going in fucking Arabia !
Come on , gang !
Come on .
- ♪ The Nefud Desert is a sand-filled ear . ♪
♪ If you fall off your camel , it cannot hear . ♪
♪ The Nefud Desert is a sand-filled ear . ♪
- ♪ But I can hear - ♪
- Listen to this , Rick .
- ♪ Lying in the night . ♪
♪ We need the boy 's life to prove that we are - ♪
- This is " Lawrence of Arabia . "
- ♪ I can hear him sleeping still in the sand . ♪
♪ I must save him so a lesser man will understand . ♪
♪ The children know this is not about a British war . ♪
- Something 's definitely happened .
We can 't just leave this .
We can 't go back on the air without something solid .
Laurel-Ann find me somebody I can put on the air .
- Well , I 've got Aline Freethy on two .
She 's hysterical ,
but she seems to be in the middle of things .
- Okay , well , see if you can calm her down .
See what she 's got .
Why is there nothing anywhere on this ?
- ♪ Nefud Desert is a sand-filled ear . ♪
- These are Bedouin girls .
- Grant , we 're trying for eyewitnesses .
We 'll have somebody for you when your singers are done .
- ♪ Are we sleeping ? ♪
- This is Osama bin Laden .
- ♪ From the sun . ♪
♪ Are we dead ? ♪
♪ Are we sleeping ? ♪
♪ I will wake the fallen boy . ♪
♪ I will not forsake a trust . ♪
♪ I will reach back across the dunes ♪
♪ and stir the desert 's heart ♪
♪ and fill it with your blood . ♪
♪ It is a sacred trust ♪
♪ to fill it with your blood . ♪
- [ ululating ]
- Fuck you , Rick .
- That 's it .
- Okay , now , that was ...
Tony Burgess , Maureen Hinkle , Nancy Freethy ,
Jay Pullman , and Colin Pullman
singing " The Nefud Desert . "
- I can 't remember how it ends .
I can 't remember how it ends .
- How what ends , Farraj ?
- It just keeps starting over and over and over and over .
And it 's not called " The Lawrence and the Table , " is it ?
Not anymore , no .
No .
Prah , prah , prah , prah ,
prah , prah , prah , prah ,
prah , prah , prah , prah .
- Okay , folks .
I guess that 's it .
- Okay , I 've got Steve VanDenzen .
He 's at the Mendez office ,
and he 's talking about a mob or a parade or something .
- He 's very excited . - Okay , any word from Ken ?
- Nothing . - Shit .
Okay , I 'm gonna keep trying Roseland .
See if you can get the straight talk from VanDenzen .
- Listen , I got a couple of cars -
Jeep Grand Cherokee marked at $ 24,995 .
- Sydney , there 's something very weird going on
with our girl , Farraj , there .
- Okay , you were great , Grant .
You did your job , and -
- Didn 't you hear her ?
- Yeah , I know .
I know you really wanted to stay with the story .
I needed you to buy us some time .
And I appreciate it . I really do .
So I have something now ,
and I 'm tossing it all back at you .
- Okay , great . What do you got ?
- Okay , so there 's still nothing anywhere on the wire
regarding this mob scene ,
but I 've got ten eyewitnesses in town .
We 're going live with Steve VanDenzen .
- That 's great . Fuck the wire if we got eyes .
- Okay , keep it hot , Grant .
- Girl , you got it . Hit me .
- Your beacon on the region .
- Any word from Ken ?
- Nothing .
- Welcome back , folks , to our developing story ,
where it appears that hundreds of people
have been involved in a riot
in and around the offices of Dr. John Mendez .
You heard our own Ken Loney describe the violent scene .
We now go live to eyewitness Steve VanDenzen .
Steve ?
Steve VanDenzen ?
- Get out ! Go !
Go ! Go ! Go !
- Okay , I 'm afraid we 've lost the signal from Steve VanDenzen .
We 'll try and return to him later .
But we have just had a report from a Pontypool resident
that confirms , indeed , a mob was spotted
earlier today headed through town ,
headed toward the offices of Dr. John Mendez .
- Apparently they were moving -
- And they are -
we 're still waiting for word
exactly what motivated this crowd ,
this mob , to organize in a -
- Grant , I think people are fucking with us .
- You know , it 's very difficult at this moment
to get a fix on what has happened ,
but clearly-well , you heard our own reporter Ken Loney earlier .
- I don 't know , Grant . I don 't know .
We can 't get Ken back on the line .
- We are still trying to -
- This is completely fucked .
I don 't know what 's going on .
- CLSY .
Can you slow down ? I can 't understand what -
- CLSY . - Okay , hello ?
- We have also learned that some of the perpetrators
are speaking in bizarre ways .
They 're babbling in ways that no one understands .
We don 't know if this is a way of trying to terrorize people .
We don 't know .
- Hello , CLSY ?
I 'm sorry . What did you just -
- We still do not have an official version
of these events ,
but it has been reported that up to 75 people are dead .
- Sounds honest . It is honest .
- And at least twice -
- I have CBC and CFRB on the line wanting to talk to you .
- We now take you to Constable Bob Roseland
of the Pontypool unit of the O.P.P.
He 's on the line live .
Constable Roseland , what 's happening out there ?
- At 7 : 00 this morning ,
our officers answered a 911 call
to the Golden Dawn facility
to discover a large number of people
occupying the building .
They seemed to be trying to get in to the elderly woman 's room .
And this woman has since died
from incidental injuries -
- Okay , Grant , apparently these people were chanting something .
It 's a little creepy .
Chanting something -
- And what were they saying ?
- They were repeating things .
This woman was saying - and she 's all senile ,
so she 's babbling about Hitler and some hurricane -
- Crazy talk . Get out , Grant .
- Okay , thank you , Constable Roseland .
Now , we are also hearing about a herd -
Well , that 's how it 's being described .
A herd of people near the edge of the forest
near Highway 26 in Edenvale .
Where 's Edenvale , Sydney ?
- It 's northwest .
- Now , Edenvale is northwest of us .
And also between here and there -
- Okay , please keep holding .
- A couple with their two young children
have been trapped in their car
under a mountain , a mountain , of people .
- Apparently , Grant , I 'm being told
by Rachael Jones that these people
were imitating windshield wipers .
They 're making the sound of windshield wipers .
- Um -
- CLSY .
- Haven 't been able to actually see the car in over an hour .
- Can I put you on hold for a sec ?
- They sound like bugs .
- Sydney , I 've got BBC World on the line .
- BBC ?
- There are a growing number of eyewitness accounts ,
but we still have had nothing official .
No press conference has been held -
- Grant , I 've got Nigel Healing for you .
- What ?
- Yeah , Nigel Healing from the BBC .
Don 't talk to me . Talk to him .
Listen , our air , their air . They want to go live .
Let 's just do it .
- We are talking to Grant Mazzy , the news radio anchor
from Pontypool , Ontario , in Canada ,
who broke this story .
Mr. Mazzy , are you there ?
- Grant .
- Yes , Nigel , hi .
- Mr. Mazzy , is it true that French Canadian soldiers
have set up roadblocks preventing people from leaving
and entering your area -
- I haven 't heard anything about this , Grant .
- I don 't think he knows what he 's talking about .
- And if so , does this have anything to do
with your country 's history of separatist terror groups ?
- Well , uh ...
Nigel , none of that is true .
The military , of course , is rumored to be involved .
And of course , the police are responding as we speak ,
but from what we can tell , there 's nothing organized ,
nothing political ,
certainly not terrorist or separatist .
- But , Mr. Mazzy , this certainly looks like an insurgency of some kind .
Large groups of people are involved .
But if it 's not organized , as you say ,
and it 's not political ,
then can you help our viewers at home understand
exactly what it is we 've been reporting on ?
- He 's good .
- Uh , Nigel , the honest truth is
that no one has officially come out ahead on this .
We simply do not know .
- There you have it .
A series of strange riots
and violent mob scenes in rural Canada
that no one - I repeat , no one-can explain .
Meanwhile , reports persist that French Canadian riot police
have been called in to crush this insurgency .
- Ah , fuck you , Nigel .
He knows nothing .
- Where are you ?
Okay , I 'm gonna pass you through to Syd .
I 've got Ken .
- Ken .
- That was Nigel Healing from our affiliate station BBC .
We now go to Ken Loney live in the field in Pontypool .
Our reporter , Ken Loney .
Ken ? Ken , are you there , Ken ?
- Uh , yes .
Yes , I 'm here .
Send someone . I 'm not safe here .
- Not safe where , Ken ?
- Oh , don 't say where he is , in case something happens .
- Grain silo .
I 'm near the train tracks . It 's the big silos , not the little ones .
I ran here from the entranceway
of the Nimigon National Park .
They came after me .
You got to send police .
- There is no contacting the police , Grant .
There is no reaching the police .
- Can you tell us what happened ?
What 's happening there , Ken ?
- I 'll tell you this .
I just saw -
I 've seen things today
that are gonna ruin the rest of my natural life , Grant .
And I 'm scared .
I 'm scared .
- Ken ?
Ken , listen to me .
It sounds like you 're okay where you are .
So don 't move , and you just stay there .
And we 're gonna - - Cannibals .
And some were naked and -
and like dogs .
And their eyes .
That look ; it 's just -
startled , kind of wild .
- Oh , God , Grant .
- Okay , Ken - - No , no , no , no .
You don 't understand .
I 'm looking through a little door .
There 's a little door at the base of the door ,
some kind of cat door or something ,
and I can see the -
just-okay , let me move so I can see the -
No !
Look out !
Oh , God , they 're pulling two people out of a van .
- Who are they , Ken ? Who are they ?
- There 's a bunch of them .
They 're people , but they 're crazy .
They 're pulling these two out of the van .
Oh , my God !
They 're - they 're biting them .
They 're actually carrying them to the ground
in their mouths .
I can 't -
Can 't see .
They 're biting . They 're just biting .
They look like a school of fish ,
like a frenzy of piranha .
It 's almost as if - it 's like -
it 's just how it looks , I guess .
But it looks like these people are trying to climb
or eat their way inside .
And they 're so desperate ,
like they have to be inside -
One has his entire leg and another-his arm -
it 's right inside .
- Okay , stop this , Grant .
- They 're pulling themselves apart !
- Okay , Grant , stop this now .
- Ah !
Holy shit .
He heard that . One of them looked over .
He heard me .
Oh , he 's coming . Holy shit .
I got to hide . He 's running .
He 's running .
[ loud clattering over headphones ]
- Ken , get out of there .
Ken ?
Ken , it 's Grant . Are you injured ?
Have you been hurt ?
- No , no .
Just lying here .
I 'm in the dark .
It crashed through the wall .
It was Mary Gault 's boy ,
her big teenager Jessie or Jake or something .
- Oh , my God , Jessie .
- It was him . He had no hands .
The kid had no hands .
- Grant , let 's stop this now .
- What 's he doing now ?
- Not on the air , Grant .
I 'm not gonna listen to somebody get killed on the air .
- He 's looking at me .
I think he can 't move .
He must 've broken some bones .
I can see his eyes .
He can 't move .
Wait , wait .
I think he 's -
- No . - Hang on .
- Ken ?
Whatever you do , don 't go near him .
- He 's whispering something .
He 's saying something .
I 'm gonna get closer
and see if I can just hear what he 's saying .
- No , I wouldn 't do that , Ken .
[ loud static over headphones ]
[ man speaking French ]
[ loud static over speakers ]
- What the hell was that ?
- Ken ? - They cut into our signal .
- Ken ?
Do we still have Ken ?
- No , we 've lost Ken .
- We 've lost Ken , folks .
We are working on a translation
of the message we just received live on the air .
- It 's something about " avoid family members , "
" talk only to babies . "
It 's crazy shit .
- However working on a translation .
- Okay , I got it .
- It 's on your screen .
- Okay , we have the translation .
Now , I 'm gonna read this , reminding our listeners
that the source has not yet been identified
and early analysis has identified this
as possibly a hoax of some kind .
And I 'll remind you that the source was not us ,
and indeed , we do not know the source .
" For your safety ,
" please avoid contact with close family members
" and restrain from the following :
" all terms of endearment ,
such as hugging or - "
- Sydney .
Yeah , Bob , what 's up ?
- " And rhetorical discourse .
" For greater safety , please avoid the English language .
Please do not translate this message . "
What do you got ?
- That was Bob Roseland .
He said that we have to stay inside .
Pontypool is under quarantine .
Everybody has to stay inside at all times .
- Did you get -
- Hello ? Hello ?
- Yeah , did you get that ?
- Ken ? - Did you get -
I 'm sending you some audio with my phone .
- Oh , thank God . Ken , are you there ?
- Did you get that ?
- No , Ken , I didn 't get it .
I don 't get anything right now .
- Okay , okay , let 's -
I 'm gonna try that again .
Okay , listen .
And keep in mind -
picture this .
This is -
what you 're about to hear is coming from Mary Gault 's
big teenage boy .
He 's lying here in the dark
with his body - it 's broken to pieces .
And his wrists , I can see them .
They 're stumps . They 're not stumps .
They 're pointing up at his sides .
- No , Grant , what are we doing ?
- Listen , listen , listen , listen .
- [ baby voice ] Mama .
Help me .
Mommy .
- Did you hear that ?
I don 't even know how he 's doing that .
It 's sounds like there 's a child ,
it 's screaming inside his breath .
- Is this actually happening , Ken ?
- Easy , Grant . Easy .
- All right .
That was our own Ken Loney .
[ car horn honking over headphones ]
What ?
That was our own Ken -
Ken Loney .
- You 're on the radio , ain 't you ?
- Interviewing -
- On the radio , you big -
- A screaming baby coming from Mary Gault 's
eldest son 's last dying gasps .
- " Mazzy in the Morning . "
Grant . - What ?
- Grant ?
Fishin ' . We 're goin ' fishin ' .
- It was a little baby , tiny little baby .
- Grant ? - What ?
[ squealing sounds ]
- Okay , Grant , listen to this .
BBC is going wide with the Mendez story .
He just said " Honey . "
He just said , " Honey the missing cat poster . "
- What ?
- The Honey the missing -
Honey the missing cat .
Grant ?
Honey the missing cat poster , Grant .
Oh , jeez .
Laurel-Ann , let 's go out .
School closures .
Five , four -
- School buses throughout Prince Edward County
and Victoria are not running today ,
but some schools are remaining open .
Bing Public School -
- Are you finding this funny , Syd ?
Are you laughing ?
- It 's not a joke , Grant .
I 'm beginning to think this is not a joke .
Everything that I 've got looks real .
- The cat ?
- Nigel Healing said , apparently -
- Nigel Healing said " apparently " -
Can you fucking hear yourself ?
- Don 't yell at me , Grant .
- Oh , I 'm sorry .
Syd , you know , I 'm having a lot of trouble here believing this .
- I know , Grant , I know .
Me too , okay ?
- I mean , is somebody pulling my leg ?
Are they , like , taking the piss out of me , you know ?
I mean , is it some kind of stunt ?
- Well , there 's some dead people -
A pretty big number , I think .
- Look , I got to get out of here , okay ?
I 'm having a lot of trouble believing
that this is actually happening , okay , so -
I 'm just going to get out of here for a minute .
- Grant , Grant , I just need you to sit back down .
You stay there , okay ?
I need you in your chair .
You need to sit back down .
- Okay , we 've got crickets .
- Laurel-Ann , go to pre-tape .
- What pre-tape ? - I don 't care , anything .
Just go to pre-tape .
Where are you going ?
- Mrs. French 's cat is missing .
The signs are posted all over town .
- Okay , um , you know , I need you back in the chair , okay ?
- Uh , no , I got to - aw , man .
I got to go outside and take a look at -
- Grant ?
Grant , I can 't have dead air .
- Syd , does this have something to do with me ?
- What are you talking about ?
- This .
I mean , why ?
Why are they carrying dead cat pictures , huh ?
Huh ?
I mean , is this me going crazy ?
You know , I need to feel that there 's something solid .
I need to confirm -
I need to know that there 's more happening to everyone
than what 's happening to just me .
You know ?
- Grant , come on .
- You !
You are fucking with me !
You are fucking with my head !
And , you , don 't you fuck with me !
Well , Norman Mailer , he had an interesting theory -
- Grant !
Grant , come on .
It 's dangerous .
Don 't go , Grant .
There 's people dying , Grant .
- Well , I got to take a look out there .
I got to see what 's going on .
- We 'll go when the blizzard 's done .
I need you on the radio .
Don 't walk out on me , Grant .
Please , I need you !
Shit !
Fine , just fucking fall apart .
- It 's nothing .
It 's just a cold , cold , cold day .
- Oh , shit !
- What you looking at ?
- Shit ! Move !
- Don 't you walk out - - Don 't you walk out on me .
- What the hell is that ?
- I need you . - We have an enemy , sir .
- Laurel-Ann , we got an enemy .
- Okay , what 's going on ?
Those are my words .
- Don 't walk out on me , Grant .
- What is going on ?
- Sydney , Sydney .
Hey , Sydney . - I 'm scared .
- Sydney , listen , I 'm scared too .
- Don 't you walk out on me .
- You 're cut .
Hey , Laurel-Ann , we got a first-aid kit ?
- Yeah , okay .
- Sydney , focus here .
Focus . Look at me .
Where are your kids ?
- They 're with him . They 're in the city .
- That 's 100 kilometers away . They 're safe , right ?
- Oh , God , yeah . - They 're safe .
Okay , we got work to do .
I 'm going back on the radio .
This is a hell of a shift , Sydney .
What 's up first ?
- Obits . - Obits , okay .
But I got nothing taped .
- Okay , we 'll go live .
- Live , that 's what I like to hear .
Let 's go .
Gwendolyn Parker was taken from this life in her 45th year
by her beloved husband Stanley , who left this world suddenly
at the hand of family members Fiona and Michael ,
who then died at each other 's hands
in their 12th and 17th years , respectively .
Janice Gwynn has departed from her abiding husband
and by his own hand in the 34th year of her life .
Jack Gwynn survived long enough to add four names :
Paul Hieghton , 43 , Alice Hieghton , 42 ,
Brenda Hieghton , 12 , and young Jesse Hieghton , 10 ,
to a list of passages before himself losing his life
as the result of an accident .
Greg Olan , 56 , has been killed by Yolanda Olan , 61 ,
who also removed Frieda Olan , 81 ,
Patsy Olan , 12 , John Freethy , 33 ,
Peter Stamp , 38 , and Leslie Reid , 42 ,
who had , between them , caused the untimely passings
of Joel Froth , 67 , Sandra Weydon , 23 ,
Tim Drummond , 17 , Cynthia Drummond , 46 ,
Darren Drummond , 51 , and Alicia Drummond , 91 .
The Drummonds were survived on Cynthia 's side
by the Hinden family until shortly before noon today ,
when they were sadly removed from this world by a bus
driven by the recently departed Brenda Lockland , 43 ,
who was missed briefly by her husband , Gary , 37 ,
now deceased .
- You 're listening to In Memoriam on CLSY Radio .
- David and Susan Varier Jones , married 51 years ,
died suddenly in each other 's arms
by each other 's -
- Are you listening to this ?
- Jason -
- Really trying not to .
Shit .
I left my cell phone in the sound booth .
I want to talk to the kids .
When he 's got them , he turns his cell phone off
or doesn 't pick up or -
I don 't know .
- He 's a jerk .
- And has since gone missing several times .
- So did anything this crazy ever happen to you in Afghanistan ?
- No , sir .
I believe this situation I brought back in my head .
- What do you - what do you mean ?
- I don 't really know .
I 'm gonna go see if Mr. Mazzy 's missing .
Missing .
As in-miss - I mean , Mr. Mazzy .
Mr. Mazzy 's missing ,
as in ' cause he 's not here .
- Well , honey , he 's in the sound booth .
- Yeah , I know .
I just - - Okay ?
- I 'm gonna - I 'm gonna go .
[ tea kettle whistling ]
[ high-pitched whining ]
- Excuse me !
- Sorry .
Please , don 't be alarmed .
I 'm Dr. John Mendez .
I 've had a hell of a time .
I have literally been crawling on my hands and knees
throughout town all over and -
Okay , oh - don 't say anything .
Okay .
Oh , boy .
- She just started doing this .
- Um , sorry . I 'm a doctor .
We should step out .
- Laurel-Ann ? Laurel-Ann , honey , are you okay ?
- No , no , no , no .
It 's terribly urgent that we keep moving .
She 'll follow our voices .
We have to - what 's that ?
- It 's a sound booth .
- Life boat . Let 's go !
- Mister-mister - Mr. Mendez is missing Mazzy .
No , no . I 'm-I 'm Missy Mazzy .
I have to -
- We just need to get a little bit of lead time ahead of her .
Don 't worry . She doesn 't have a purpose yet .
- What 's wrong with her ? - Hurry , hurry , hurry .
- Grant , Grant , Grant .
- Jesus .
- It 's Dr. John Mendez .
- Mendez ? - Hi .
- You 're the building that exploded .
- And I think he probably has quite a story to tell .
Doctor , would you like to have a seat ?
- You mean , on the radio ? - Yeah .
- Oh , yeah , yeah , I have a story I want to tell .
- No , guys , wait .
I 'm not missing anymore .
I don 't miss Mr. Mazzy .
- I think it might be a little bit more interesting
than Nigel Healing , huh , Grant ?
- What 's going on ?
- Your friend is sick .
I 've seen a lot of this lately .
She doesn 't know it yet , but she 's hunting us .
- I don 't miss Mr. Mazzy .
I 'm not missing anymore .
Sydney !
Missing Mazzy .
- She doesn 't look -
- Okay , come on , we can 't just leave her out there .
I want to talk to her . Grant , put -
- No , no , no , no , no .
Let 's leave the sound sealed in here with us .
She might lose track of where we are if she can 't hear us .
- You are listening to the Beacon .
We are holding our own here today ,
and we are taking no prisoners , friends .
However , today we are those prisoners .
We are tired , and we are scared .
But we have live with us Dr. John Mendez .
Now , you may know him or you may recall
our own Ken Loney 's vivid account
of the violence that took place
when the mob destroyed his practice .
Now , Dr. Mendez , we 're looking to you .
You 've had some special experience with these -
with these events .
And we would like any insights that you can provide .
[ loud bang ]
- Laurel-Ann , don 't do that .
Stop .
- Oh , she 's rooting for voices .
This will grow vicious .
- I should mention that , sadly , very sadly ,
our own Homecoming Hero , Laurel-Ann Drummond ,
is right now experiencing some kind of dangerous seizures .
- I 've seen this , what your friend is experiencing .
Okay , can I - okay -
I 've seen elements of this .
She doesn 't have a victim yet .
So I 'm not sure how this will end .
I mean , a victim suicides ,
but the victim needs a victim to suicide into .
I know this is horribly upsetting to you ,
and I 'm sorry to be the bearer of such disturbing news ,
but I 've seen this violent behavior at my office all morning .
- Yeah , okay , we 're going live .
I 've got Ken . - Okay , thank you , Dr. Mendez .
We are now going to our own reporter Ken Loney .
He 's live in the field .
He 's in the grain silo near Pontypool .
Are you there , Ken ?
- I 'm here , Grant .
Ken Loney reporting from inside a grain silo .
- Ken , we were very worried about you , Ken .
- I think-I 'm okay , but the person that was in here with me ,
he has died .
- Have you been there all this time ?
- Yeah , I haven 't moved .
But you can hear crowds from time to time
passing by outside .
- Can you hear what they 're saying ?
Are they saying anything ?
- I have . Yeah , you can hear them .
A group went by about an hour ago ,
and they were talking about U-boats .
Well , they weren 't talking really .
They were just sort of chanting something about ,
" Look out for U-boats . Look out for U-boats .
Look out for U-boats . "
- Were they all saying this , Ken ?
- Yeah , yeah , all of them .
It 's a symbol of the disorder .
- A symbol of the disorder ?
You mean a symptom ?
- It 's a simple -
Uh , it 's -
I have a problem .
- What 's happening there , Ken ?
Do you need to get to someplace safer ?
- No , no , that 's not it .
I - I -
- What 's going on , Ken ?
- It 's gonna - It 's gonna sound weird .
I can 't stop thinking -
Do you have a sample ?
- I 'm sorry ?
A sample ?
A sample of what ?
- Just a sample .
I think a simple kind of sample .
Mm , mm .
This is what I 'm saying .
I need to -
I can 't stop some sample -
some -
some sample .
Sample of what I 'm trying -
sample of what I 'm trying to say .
Do you -
- Just try to stay calm , Ken .
- What I 'm trying to say .
Grant ? Grant ?
- Ken ? Ken ?
- I was gonna try to - try to -
- Can you think ?
- I can 't . I can 't .
- Stick to simple questions , simple .
- Simple questions , simple .
Simple . Simple .
- That 's it . He 's gone .
This is what he is now .
He 's just a crude radio signal .
He 's seeking .
- Simple . Simple .
Simple . Simple .
- I think it 's time to say good-bye , Grant ,
to our man in the Sunshine Chopper .
- Simple . Simple .
- All right , good-bye , Ken .
Good-bye from all of us , everyone listening .
I hope you can hear me , Ken .
Good-bye .
- He 's gone .
Well , I mean , he 's gone somewhere .
- I 'm so sorry , Sydney .
Ken was - he was -
he was a real good friend of yours , wasn 't he ?
- Oh , he wasn 't a friend .
Ken Loney was a pedophile .
I mean , not really a pedophile .
We just never let our kids go anywhere near him .
It 's - this is -
it 's just that I 've known him 17 years .
It 's just a long , long time .
Shit .
I wasn 't a very good obit .
- What 's this now ?
- Ah , mm .
Ah , sorry .
Uh , folks ...
we 're still here ,
and , well , Laurel-Ann has joined us again .
And she 's looking worse .
She looks like she 's been trying to eat something .
- Stop .
- You sure she can 't hear us .
- No , no , she can 't .
Can she read lips ?
- Good question .
Read lips .
- What ?
- No , I mean , that 's a very interesting thing you just said .
Can they read lips ?
- Really ?
Well , interesting how ? How ?
I should remind our listeners , we are talking to -
- No . No , it can 't be .
It can 't be .
it 's impossible .
- What 's impossible , Doctor ?
- It 's viral .
That much is clear .
But not of the blood .
Not blood . Not in the air .
Not on or even in our bodies .
It is here .
- Where ?
- It is in words .
Not all words .
Not all speaking .
But in some .
Some words are infected .
And it spreads out when the contaminated word is spoken .
- Oh .
- We are witnessing the emergence of a new arrangement for life ,
and our language is its host .
It could have sprung spontaneously
out of a perception .
If it found its way into language ,
it could leap into reality itself , changing everything .
It may be boundless .
It may be a God bug .
- Okay , Dr. Mendez , look , I don 't even believe in UFOs ,
so I got to stop you there with that God bug thing .
- Oh , really ?
Well , you know , that 's very sensible ,
because UFOs don 't exist .
But I assure you , there is a monster loose ,
and it 's bouncing through our language ,
frantically trying to keep its host alive .
- Is this transmission itself -
- No , no , no , no , no .
If the bug enters us ,
it does not enter by making contact with our eardrum .
No .
It enters us when we hear the word and we understand it .
Understand ?
It is when the word is understood ...
that the virus takes hold .
And it copies itself in our understanding .
- Well ...
Should we be talking about this ?
- What are we talking about ?
- Should we be talking at all ?
- Well , to be safe , no , probably not .
Talking is risky .
And , well , talk radio is high risk ,
so we should stop .
- But -
we need to tell people about this .
People need to know .
We have to get this out .
- Well , it 's your call , Mr. Mazzy .
But let 's just hope what you 're getting out there
isn 't going to destroy your world .
[ suspenseful music ]
[ people shouting indistinctly ]
[ banging on door ]
[ glass shattering ]
[ Mazzy humming softly ]
- The whole world can hear you breathing .
It 's fine .
Your breathing , that 's your top news story .
Can 't take your breath away if you 're breathing .
Breathe , breathe .
- Go to Muzak , Grant , Muzak .
Can 14 .
- Seems we 're still talking .
Should we make our moratorium official ?
[ rhythmic buzzing sound ]
- Hello ?
- Here she comes .
- Hi , honey . Hi , honey .
Hi , sweetie .
Are you and Brend - you and Brendan are okay ?
Oh , I miss you too , so much , honey .
I 'll see you tomorrow , huh ?
That 's great , honey .
That 's my -
uh-huh .
Is your daddy there , honey ?
Can I talk to him real fast ?
Honey , I didn 't forget to call .
I just couldn 't get through , sweetheart .
- She shouldn 't be talking to anyone who calls .
And no " sweethearts , " please .
She should be breathing more .
Breathe , breathe , breathe .
Just talking out loud . Just talking out loud .
- Can you please put your daddy on ?
- Oh , damn .
- It 's not your birthday today , Lulu .
It 's Valentine 's Day , sweetie .
It 's not really a good time right now , sweetie .
Can you just put your daddy on ?
♪ Happy Valentine 's Day to you , Lulu . ♪
♪ ' Cause I love you . ♪
[ loud thud ]
Lulu ?
Hello ?
Hello , honey ?
Shit .
- [ mumbling incoherently ]
- Phone lines are dead .
- Something strange is happening to her .
I haven 't seen this before .
- Mazzy , Mazzy , Mazzy -
[ gagging ]
- I forgot to give her a Valentine 's Day card .
- Grant , thanks for the Valentine card .
I didn 't say anything . I 'm sorry .
It was really nice .
- Mazzy , Mazzy -
[ burps ]
- So this is what happens when a victim can 't find a victim .
This is the fate they 're trying to escape .
My God , that was impressive .
Oh , and singularly monstrous .
Defies compression .
I 'm sorry . I 'm sorry .
Wow .
Breathe , breathe , breathe .
Oh , here they come now .
There must be hundreds of them
pressed against the walls of this building .
What we need is a flame thrower .
- I thought we weren 't supposed to talk .
- Yes , yes , yes . You 're right , you 're right .
[ no audible dialogue ]
[ hands pounding on glass ]
[ Mazzy huffing quietly into microphone ]
- [ quietly ] Sydney Briar is alive .
Sydney Briar is alive .
[ people repeating words at once ]
- I looped it .
- [ over loudspeaker ] Sydney Briar is alive .
Sydney Briar is alive .
- [ tittering ]
We can breathe again .
Breathe .
[ speaking foreign language ]
It 's only the English language that 's infected .
Oh , breathe , breathe !
Breathe , breathe .
[ laughing maniacally ]
- [ speaking French ]
- Sydney Briar is alive .
Sydney Briar is alive ...
- Grant , run ! Run now !
Grant , run . Run now .
Run . Grant , run .
- Come get me .
Come get me !
Come get me .
Get me .
[ girl exhaling slowly ]
[ Sydney sobbing ]
- Sydney Briar is alive ...
No .
Okay , okay .
- I 'm not gonna kill the doctor .
No .
God .
- Okay .
- Shit .
Merde !
[ La Marseillaise playing loudly over speakers ]
♪ ♪
- [ speaking foreign language ]
[ music stops ]
[ static hissing ]
- Grant ! - Here he comes !
[ speaking French ]
[ all chanting and yelling ]
- Sydney Briar 's alive .
- Sydney Briar is alive .
- Lock the door .
- Sydney Briar 's alive !
Sydney Briar 's alive !
Sydney Briar is alive !
- Grant .
Grant ?
He 's saving us .
- Sydney Briar is alive !
[ static hissing and beeping ]
[ helicopter blades thrumming ]
- Mr. Mazzy , is it true that French Canadian soldiers
have set up roadblocks preventing people from leaving
and entering your area ?
And if so , does this have anything to do
with your country 's history of separatist terror groups ?
- Why didn 't you speak up ?
- French !
Continue .
Oh , for Christ 's sake .
Give it up , Grant .
Oh , there is no secret escape plan hidden in the words
that Nigel said to you .
Oh .
Stop that .
- Can you help our viewers at home understand -
understanding - understand -
- Syd ?
- We 're not talking . I 'm drunk .
This is how my last relationship ended .
- How do you stop understanding this ?
- Oh , God .
You 're gonna eat me soon , aren 't you ?
It 's okay .
You be the killer .
I don 't want to be the killer .
- There 's something Dr. Mendez said , you see ?
He said that understanding a word copies the virus .
How do you not understand a word ?
How do you -
- Okay , you are talking a lot right now .
- How do you not understand something ?
How-somebody understands automatically .
How do you take , you know , like a word -
how do you make it strange ?
- We are gonna have killers in here soon
if you keep killing your own rules , Grant .
Grant ? I 'll kill the killers .
- See , it 's not understanding what disinfects it .
See , that 's the question .
If it disinfects it , then how , without distorting ,
how do you do that ?
- You kill the word that 's killing you .
- Oh , you kill the word that 's killing you .
That 's good ; that 's good . You repeat it .
Yeah , I remember as a kid , I used to -
I used to repeat words over and over and over again
till they were incomprehensible .
You think that 's what it is ?
Is that why they 're repeating things ?
Is it some kind of a immune system response ?
- You have to kill -
all the killing .
- Yeah , but it doesn 't work , because they repeat the word ,
and then they still get sick .
So how do you make it unrecognizable ?
How ?
And what word ?
- Kill .
- Kill , kill , kill .
Kill , kill .
- Syd ?
Are you okay ?
- Kill . - Are you okay ?
- Kill , kill , kill .
- Okay . - Kill , kill , kill .
- Syd , Syd .
Sydney , I think you got an infected word .
You 're infected .
But we know the word .
Don 't say anything . Don 't say anything .
No , no , no . Stop .
Stop . We know the word .
- Kill , kill , kill .
- Okay , kill isn 't kill .
Sydney , kill isn 't kill .
It isn 't kill . Kill isn 't kill .
Kill isn 't kill . Kill isn 't kill .
It isn 't kill .
Kill isn 't kill .
Oh , God , I don 't know , I don 't know , I don 't know .
Okay , okay .
Kill is blue .
Kill is wonderful .
Kill is loving .
Kill is baby .
Kill is mayonnaise garden .
Kill is beautiful morning .
Kill is everything you ever wanted .
Kill is - kill is -
Kill is kiss .
Kill is -
Is that it ?
Kill is kiss ?
Kill is kiss . Kill is kiss .
Kill is kiss .
What is kill ?
- Kiss .
Kill me .
- What ?
- Kill me .
Kill is kiss . Kill is kiss .
Okay .
Okay , I feel better .
- Yeah .
- I feel better .
- Me too .
- Okay , what just happened ?
Seriously , what just - seriously , what just happened ?
- We just kissed .
- I know , I know .
I know .
What just happened also ?
- Sydney , I think -
something big just happened .
I think I just cured you .
Sydney , this is big .
This is huge .
- Where are you going ?
- We got to let people know about this .
We just found a way out of this .
- Shit , Grant , wait . Listen to me , Grant .
What are we doing ? What are we doing here ?
- Come on , girl . One last show .
- One last what ?
Grant ?
Grant , listen to me .
We 're not supposed to be even out here .
What are we doing out here ? It 's not safe .
- Syd , we 're gonna save the fucking world , right now .
How you feeling ?
- Well , you don 't even know that you did that
or what you did or how you did it .
Listen , Grant , stop .
Listen , you 're way ahead of yourself .
We 're okay , okay ?
We 're okay . We 're safe up there .
We just don 't talk . We have to stay safe .
What Mendez said , let 's make it easy .
Shit , Grant , we shut up or die !
- People are already dying , Syd .
And we 've been playing Muzak .
Do we really want to provide a genocide with elevator music ?
- Shit .
- I don 't know what I did up there , Syd , but I got to try .
Because if I don 't - - Okay .
- What ?
- Okay , okay . I said , " Okay . "
- Yeah .
- Oh , you 're killing me , Mazzy .
Now get going . Go , go , go .
- You there ? You there ?
- Yeah , yeah , I 'm here .
I 'm here . I 'm here , Grant .
- Hello ? - Grant ?
- Yeah , yeah . - Okay .
- Okay , we 're gonna do what we can .
Now , that French thing , that French thing ,
he said terms of endearment and baby talk .
Okay , and we got your word .
We know how to clean that one up , right ?
And what was Laurel-Ann babbling ?
- I don 't know . I don 't remember .
0 No , look , Ken Loney , he was saying " sample " ?
Was that it , " sample " ?
Okay , we need a list . Can you make a list ?
- There 's no time for a list , Grant .
It 's gonna confuse people .
What are you planning to do ?
- Okay , put me on , put me on , come on .
- You 're on .
- Hello , Pontypool .
This is Grant Mazzy here , and today , as usual ,
we 're taking no prisoners .
In fact , today , folks , we set those prisoners free .
So here we go , folks .
" Kill " is " kiss . "
" Kill " is definitely " kiss . "
Now , sample -
" sample " is " staple . "
- Too specific , Grant .
- Listen to me , folks .
Everything is something else , okay ?
If you are saying " happy , " it means " sad . "
Happy means - no , that 's the opposite .
It can 't be that . Okay , it can 't be that .
" Happy " is " handy . "
" Happy 's " " handy . "
Move things around , people , just move ' em around .
It 's -
You have to stop understanding , stop understanding
what you are saying .
Stop understanding and listen to me .
Sample -
sample is a color .
Sample is a color and a number .
- Okay , no , Grant , no , Grant , You 're making sense , okay ?
If you say " don 't understand , " it defeats the purpose .
- Okay , okay , here we go .
[ man speaking French ]
The sky is a person .
Laughter is walking .
Yellow is crowded .
Friends are verbs .
- Sounds like shitty haiku , Grant .
I may be wrong , but I don 't think we 're saving the world
with shitty haiku .
- Okay , for Christ 's sake . Everybody 's a critic .
Help me out here .
Cling !
Intake .
- Trespass ! - Sniper .
- Swimming . - Tomorrow .
- Fidelity . - Monologue .
- Savage . - Sausage .
- Tomorrow . - Money .
- Ceiling . - Uh , I don 't -
rhinoceros .
- Laughter .
- Shit !
They 're just shooting people , Grant .
They 're just killing people .
- Stop killing people !
You got to stop killing people !
You got to stop !
You got to stop , stop , stop !
Just listen to me .
I said , " Listen to me . "
- I think everyone 's dead .
- You 're just killing scared people .
It 's what you always do .
You 're killing scared people .
You are like dogs .
You smell fear , and you pounce .
Well , what the fuck happened today , folks ?
Someone took a buzz saw to your middle
and they pulled out a wheelin ' devil ,
and they spilled it right across your anthill .
But you know what , friends ?
We were never making sense .
And today , today , when Armageddon leached out
into your good , good mornings ,
you know what ?
It 's just another day ,
another day in Pontypool .
The sun came up .
You did what you did yesterday .
And it 's exactly what you 'll do tomorrow .
Today 's news , folks ,
today 's late-breaking , developing ,
just-across-my-desk news story is this :
It 's not the end of the world , folks .
It 's just the end of the day .
This is Grant Mazzy for CLSY Radio Nowhere .
And I 'm still here , you cocksuckers .
[ distant explosions ]
[ man speaking French ]
- Police are warning that travel between towns
in central Ontario has been restricted .
The prime minister is scheduled to address the nation
this evening at 9 : 00 ,
and in this announcement , he is going to declare marshal -
- CLSY 's morning DJ Grant Mazzy was heard speaking
incoherently just minutes before that station 's signal was -
- Just up this normally busy highway ,
beyond the roadblock that prevents us from getting any closer ,
sits the normally quiet town of Pontypool ,
the scene of today 's Valentine 's Day massacre .
- I mean , that 's what I was , a loony .
The whole pattern in my head is off .
I feel better now .
I 'm having a coffee .
I 'm gonna take the dog out for a walk and clear my head , but -
- You can almost see the curve of the Earth , a horizon .
Well , what do you think would happen
if you started to identify with , say , the 12th you out there ?
- You 're listening to Soft Hits Radio in Peterborough .
And we have breaking news over our city this morning .
- As of 10 : 00 a.m. this morning ,
O.P.P. reports an alarming number of community crimes ,
vandalism , looting ,
and numerous assaults widespread across Peterborough .
We believe that this is related to the Pontypool incident
but want to assure the public that what is happening there
is not happening here .
I repeat , the events of February 14th in Pontypool
are not being repeated -
- Or something , ' cause , like , my neighbor
kept on repeating , " What are you saying , "
again and again and again .
And it 's like , I don 't know what 's going on here .
- Thank you .
Can you tell me anything else that 's happened ?
- Families up this highway , stores , and churches
and one assumes the same tight fabric
that binds all the small communities
dotting this part of the country .
Now everything that we find familiar out here
at this safe distance ,
in all likelihood , gone ,
just up this barren stretch of Ontario highway .
One can only hope that the disease ,
if that 's indeed what it was ,
killed them before we had to .
- No , but the wife can talk me crazy ,
my teenage kid too , except the opposite .
He hasn 't spoken a complete sentence to me
since last June .
Anyway , yeah , we 're all driving each other nuts .
- I was watching the TV ,
and they had a brief little thing on it
saying that there 's an outbreak or something ,
but I mean , like , I don 't know .
I don 't see any vaccination trucks
or anything like you see in the movies .
I saw that " Outbreak " movie there a few years back .
I rented it .
And it 's not quite like that .
I don 't know what to think here .
- I wasn 't saying that it 's funny .
I knew Grant Mazzy . I respected the man .
And I think he would want us to ask questions .
He would want us to find out what is really happening ,
what 's real .
- And that 's the latest from Kandahar .
In other news , French Canadian riot police
have successfully contained the violent uprising
in the small town in Ontario , Canada ,
Pontypool , Pontypool , Pontypool .
Pontypool .
- Let 's get out of here .
- Where are we going ?
- I can 't play by the establishment rules any longer .
My patience has worn thin .
We 're breaking the limits , stealing cars ,
leaving the world behind to figure out
what they believe is black and white .
- But what about - - What about -
What about , what about ?
It 's not a good anti-establishment way
to begin a question .
- My name .
- My name too .
- Johnny Dead Eyes .
- Lisa the Killer .
- Where are we going , Johnny ?
- To a new place that isn 't even there yet .
- And then ?
- Then we steal the loot and knock boots in the free world , baby .
- Okay .
Okay , baby .